Today I'm going to show you an electric vehicle
اليوم سوف أريكم مركبة كهربائية
that weighs less than a bicycle,
تزن أقل من دراجة،
that you can carry with you anywhere,
والتي يمكنك حملها معك في أي مكان،
that you can charge off a normal wall outlet in 15 minutes,
والتي يمكنك شحنها في 15 دقيقة عن طريق مقبس كهربائي عادي في الحائط،
and you can run it for 1,000 kilometers
ويمكنك قيادتها لمسافة 1000 كيلومتر
on about a dollar of electricity.
بحوالي دولار للكهرباء.
But when I say the word electric vehicle,
ولكن عندما أقول كلمة مركبة كهربائية،
people think about vehicles. They think about cars
تفكر الناس في المركبات. تفكر في السيارات
and motorcycles and bicycles, and the vehicles that you use every day.
والدراجات النارية والدراجات الهوائية، والمركبات التي تستخدمها كل يوم.
But if you come about it from a different perspective,
ولكن إذا نظرت فيها من منظور مختلف،
you can create some more interesting,
يمكنك صناعة بعض الأمور الأكثر إثارةً ،
more novel concepts.
و أفكارغير مألوفة جداً.
So we built something.
لذا قمنا ببناء شيء.
I've got some of the pieces in my pocket here.
عندي بعض القطع في جيبي هنا.
So this is the motor.
هذا هو المحرك.
This motor has enough power to take you
هذا المحرك لديه ما يكفي من القوة ليأخذك
up the hills of San Francisco at about 20 miles per hour,
أعلى تلال سان فرانسيسكو في حوالي 20 ميلاً في الساعة،
about 30 kilometers an hour,
في حوالي 30 كم في الساعة،
and this battery, this battery right here
وهذه البطارية، هذه البطارية هنا
has about six miles of range, or 10 kilometers,
لديها حوالي مدى ستة أميال ، أو 10 كيلومترات،
which is enough to cover about half of the car trips
وهو ما يكفي لتغطية حوالي نصف رحلات السيارة
in the U.S. alone.
في الولايات المتحدة وحدها.
But the best part about these components
ولكن أفضل جزء عن هذه المكونات
is that we bought them at a toy store.
هو أننا قمنا بشرائهم من متجر للألعاب.
These are from remote control airplanes.
هذه من طائرات التحكم عن بعد.
And the performance of these things has gotten so good
وقد أصبحت أداء هذه الأمور جيدة جداً
that if you think about vehicles a little bit differently,
إذا قكرت قليلاً في المركبات بطريقة مختلفة،
you can really change things.
يمكنك حقاً تغيير الأشياء.
So today we're going to show you one example
لذلك اليوم سوف نعرض لكم مثال واحد
of how you can use this.
عن كيف يمكنك استخدام هذا.
Pay attention to not only how fun this thing is,
لا تركز فقط على كيف هذا الشيء ممتعاً،
but also how the portability that comes with this
ولكن أيضا على كيف أن قابلية التنقل التي تأتي مع هذا
can totally change the way you interact with a city like San Francisco.
يمكنها تغير تماماً الطريقة التي تتفاعل معها في مدينة مثل سان فرانسيسكو.
(Music)
(موسيقى)
[6 Mile Range] [Top Speed Near 20mph]
[تطاق 6 أميال] [أعلى سرعة قرب 20 ميل في الساعة]
[Uphill Climbing]
[صعود التل]
[Regenerative Braking]
[امكابح تجددية]
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
(Cheers)
(هتاف)
So we're going to show you what this thing can do.
لذا سوف نظهر لكم ما يمكن لهذا الشيء فعله.
It's really maneuverable. You have a hand-held remote,
أنها حقاً قادرة على المناورة. لديك جهاز تحكم باليد،
so you can pretty easily control acceleration, braking,
لذلك يمكنك بسهولة جداً التحكم بالسرعة، بالمكابح،
go in reverse if you like, also have braking.
الذهاب في الاتجاه المعاكس إذا أردت , أيضاً لديك مكابح.
It's incredible just how light this thing is.
أنه أمر لا يصدق مقدار خفة هذا الشيء .
I mean, this is something you can pick up and carry with you
أعني، هذا شيء يمكنك التقاطه وحمله معك
anywhere you go.
في أي مكان تذهب.
So I'll leave you with one of the most compelling facts
لذا سوف اتركم مع إحدى الحقائق الأكثر إلحاحاً
about this technology and these kinds of vehicles.
عن هذه التكنولوجيا وهذه الأنواع من المركبات.
This uses 20 times less energy
هذا تستخدم طاقة أقل بعشرين مرة
for every mile or kilometer that you travel than a car,
لكل ميل أو كيلومتر تسافر فيهما بالسيارة،
which means not only is this thing fast to charge
مما يعني أنه ليس فقط هذا الشيء سريع الشحن
and really cheap to build,
وحقاً رخيصة البناء،
but it also reduces the footprint of your energy use
ولكن يقلل من البصمة الخاصة بك في إستخدام الطاقة أيضاً
in terms of your transportation.
من حيث وسائل النقل الخاصة بك.
So instead of looking at large amounts of energy needed
لذلك بدلاً من النظر إلى كميات كبيرة من الطاقة اللازمة
for each person in this room to get around in a city,
لكل شخص في هذه الغرفة لتجول في مدينة،
now you can look at much smaller amounts
الآن يمكنك أن تنظر الى كميات أقل بكثير
and more sustainable transportation.
و وسيلة تنقل مستدامة.
So next time you think about a vehicle,
لذلك في المرة القادمة عندما تفكر في مركبة،
I hope, like us, you're thinking about something new.
وآمل، مثلنا، أن تفكر عن شيء جديد.
Thank you.
شكرا.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)